<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ripx80 onexec</title><link>https://ripx80.de/</link><description>Recent content on ripx80 onexec</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>ripx80</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ripx80.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>nftables - basics</title><link>https://ripx80.de/posts/04-nftables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ripx80.de/posts/04-nftables/</guid><description>short nftables is the modern linux kernel (&amp;gt;= 3.13 nft support) packet classification framework to replace iptables.
this post will get the basics and useful commands/rules for nftables and some usecases how nftables will configured in case of a nixos system in a default way.
if you search for a advanced topic i recommend the nftables advanced router post (comming soon). need additional ideas or use cases? take a look at 50 things - nftables (comming soon).</description></item><item><title>requirements</title><link>https://ripx80.de/posts/03-requirements/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ripx80.de/posts/03-requirements/</guid><description>introduction long things short:
we are influenced by our environment the more often we have the same thing every day, the more likely they are to become a requirement track yourself what&amp;rsquo;s your hidden requirements, to be aware of stay minimal in life and technical enjoy if you have more at the time, it will not always be like this story #2 with a dull fetch throb against the from weather-garnished oak door i drew attention to myself.</description></item><item><title>privacy policy</title><link>https://ripx80.de/privacy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 16:53:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ripx80.de/privacy/</guid><description>Privacy policy Responsible person Person responsible for content in accordance with 55 Abs. 2 RStV
Daniel Rittweiler
Danziger Str. 27-35, 20099 Hamburg
Contact Telephone: +49 176 47839408
E-Mail: ripx80@protonmail.com
Website: https://ripx80.de
Scope of the processing of personal data This data protection declaration informs you about the nature, scope and purpose of the processing of personal data (hereinafter referred to as &amp;ldquo;data&amp;rdquo;) within our online offer and the websites, functions and content associated with it, as well as external online presences, such as our social media profiles (hereinafter collectively referred to as &amp;ldquo;online offer&amp;rdquo;).</description></item><item><title>Ufleku - the desire</title><link>https://ripx80.de/posts/02-ufleku-recipe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 16:11:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ripx80.de/posts/02-ufleku-recipe/</guid><description>story the desire
under the old oak marked by storms, dozing and slumbering towards the afternoon, i suddenly felt an unpleasant sensation in my left ear, at first i thought it was one of those vivid daydreams that haunted me again and again lately, leading me into dark alleys, fleeing from pursuers and dark figures. i ignored it and tried to continue in this peaceful safety of the old oak, listening to the last autumn leaves, to organize my thoughts, how it should go on and especially where.</description></item><item><title>Kernel Compiling</title><link>https://ripx80.de/posts/01-kernel-compiling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 16:46:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ripx80.de/posts/01-kernel-compiling/</guid><description>Introduction This is a short discurse about self kernel compilation on a arch system. Gentoo users are familiar with this kind of instructions or use the genkernel programm. You can find an article on archlinux
Install kernel sources and headers 1 2 3 pacman -S base-devel # only gcc and make mkdir /usr/src/linux cd /usr/src/linux download the newest kernel release, at this moment it is 4.13.0
1 2 3 wget https://www.</description></item><item><title>2022</title><link>https://ripx80.de/lib/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ripx80.de/lib/</guid><description>only for self tracking and keep motivated to read more.
reading hegels world (hegels welt) - juergen kaube think in systems - donella h. meadows auris - vincent kliesch win (nichts bleibt begraben) - harlan coben &amp;lt; pipe ego is the enemy - ryan holiday do the work - steven pressfield 365 days with self discipline - martin meadows ignore everybody - hugh macleod the war of art - steven pressfield moonwalking with einstein - joshua foer how to take smart notes - söhnke ahrens the dragonbone chair - tad williams the first law - joe abercrombie best served cold (racheklingen) - joe abercrombie blood song (das lied des blutes) - anthony ryan paradise (das verlorene paradies) - abdulrazak gurnah great expectations (große erwartungen) - charles dickens more from tad williams 2024 goal: 1/10</description></item><item><title>legal notice</title><link>https://ripx80.de/legal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ripx80.de/legal/</guid><description>Legal Notice Information in accordance with section 5 TMG Contact Telephone: +49 176 47839408
E-Mail: ripx80@protonmail.com
Website: https://ripx80.de
Person responsible for content in accordance with 55 Abs. 2 RStV
Daniel Rittweiler
Danziger Str. 27-35, 20099 Hamburg
Disclaimer Accountability for content The contents of our pages have been created with the utmost care. However, we cannot guarantee the contents&amp;rsquo; accuracy, completeness or topicality. According to statutory provisions, we are furthermore responsible for our own content on these web pages.</description></item><item><title>whoami</title><link>https://ripx80.de/whoami/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ripx80.de/whoami/</guid><description>introduction 1 2 $ whoami ripx80 - Daniel Rittweiler experience #go #rust #python #sec #linux #nix #devops #minimalist #ci #gentoo #arch #nixos #k8s #git #bmw #speaker #kernel #cmd #gamer #webdev #c #php #writer #wg #network #forensics
dmesg rip is the instruction pointer of 64-bit registers and he is interupting vector 0x80, on linux systems its used for system_calls. the pseudo name was created when i read the book &amp;ldquo;the art of exploitation&amp;rdquo; since few years and handle with the eip on 64-bit systems :-).</description></item></channel></rss>